Hello, my friends.
And welcome to the array's lesson.
This is the first data structure loss.
Think about mastering the name of this student in a class.
We basically create string as the one equal to Jack if we need to store the names of four students.
We are going to make four strings like a city, one city to city and four.
But if we have a group of students or students in of the school of a or a college in university, we
are going to make like this.
So we are going to make 400 student strength.
OK.
This is not acceptable in terms of coding and the professional code.
So if we have four hundred students, we are not going to make a 400 string.
This is as redundant.
This is not good programming and this is not good for the memory because you would allocate the memory
by the strings for that.
There is a basic solution for this problem, like storing the same data type inside an array.
So and despite making 400 strings to store the names of these, we make a one array and store these
into one, three and so on.
So all of these would be stored in and into an array.
Having my four hundred students, I took about 16 students and stored them into this.
Every so an array is a container which can hold a fixed number of items, and these items should be
of the same time.
Following are the important terms to understand the concept of array.
Do we have the element?
Each item stored in an array is called an element, so Jack is an element Sara as element adi is element,
mirror element, eve element and so on.
Index Each location of an element is an array has a numerical index, which is used to identify the
element.
So the element and index zero is Jack.
The element at index one is Sara, the in the element at Index 13 is Fathy.
So.
This is the area you should know the elements and you should know that.
The ethics now, how to declare a raise in C Java and Python in C, we we create an array and we inside
an angled bracket.
We put here how many elements it will contain and equal that parentheses, this sort of curve to you
if the girl braces.
These are.
Ten, four, five, eight and seven.
These are the elements of this array, so we are creating an entire array of five elements containing
the numbers 10, four, five, eight and seven.
Despite making five integers, we are going to declare a one as a that will store all of these valuable.
OK.
In Java, we create the same way and out of the.
But here we put that angle, the brackets here into end, and it is a small leather array that name
of the array and we declare the same numbers in Python.
It is very simple to make a in the name of a air equal angle, the brackets and the element of the FAA.
OK.
This are the these are the elements of this.
So this three declaration where result in the end creating this out of a having at index zero 10 and
index one for at index to five at index three is eight and index for seven.
As per the above, the this installation or illustration following are the important points to be considered.
Index starts with zero, always start with zero.
OK.
And Index.
And in Java or.
Or C or Python, the index starts with the zero.
OK?
The first element is at index zero.
This is very important point.
OK.
Array length is five I am talking about Java and A..
And also Python array length is five, which means it can store five elements.
And this is obvious and see so int array we have angled bracket five.
We are telling see that we are going to create an array that stores five animals.
Each element can be accessed via its anderx, so we can access this array by adding array, the name
of array and being side angle the bracket, that index of this array.
OK.